Bendix, Reinhard; Papers ger021
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Bendix, 1930-1991; 3; 275 file folders
  - Essays and lectures, 3.3
    - "Soziologische Überlegungen zum frühchristlichen Anspruch auf absolute Wahrheit", 1986; typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 28)
    - "Sociological Reflections on the Early Christian Claim to Absolute Truth", 1986; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 29)
    - "Reflections on Modern Western States and Civil Societies" (with John Bendix and Norman Furniss), 1986; ca. 1987; typescripts, reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 30)
    - "Reflections on Modern Western States and Civil Societies", Undated (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 31)
    - Convocation Address, University of California, Berkeley, Department of Political Science, 1986 May 16; typescript (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 32)
    - "The Special Position of Europe", 1986 June 5; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 33)
    - "The Emergence of Intolerance in the Western Church", 1986 June 25 (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 34)
    - "A Reading of Tocqueville's Letters", 1986 November 6; typescripts (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 35)
    - "Values and concepts in Max Weber's comparative studies", 1987; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 36)
    - "Social Science and the Kuhn Discussion", 1988 February 4; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 37)
    - "Ein Blick auf die Sozialwissenschaften", 1989; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 38)
    - "Die Rolle des Intellektuellen in der modernen Welt", 1990; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 39)
    - "Umstrittene Vernunft -- ein Bericht", 1990; reprint (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 40)
    - "State, Legitimation and 'Civil Society'".Reprint, Winter 1990-1991 (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 41)
    - Translations of articles by Bendix into Japanese, 1960 (Box 8 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 42)
  - Reviews by Bendix of works by other authors, 3.4
    - Goldstein, Kurt. "Bemerkungen über die Bedeutung der Biologie für die Soziologie anlässlich des Autoritätsproblems", 1936; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 1)
    - Elias, Norbert.Ueber den Prozess der Zivilisation, 1939; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 2)
    - Ulich, Robert.Fundamentals of Democratic Education, 1940; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 3)
    - Chamberlin, William Henry.The World's Iron Age, 1941; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 4)
    - Marcuse, Herbert.Reason and Revolution, 1941; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 5)
    - Undated, typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 6)
      Russell, Bertrand. Power: A New Social Analysis (1938); Ferrero, Guglielmo. The Principles of Power (1942).
    - Hagen, Paul.Will Germany Crack?, 1942; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 7)
    - Leonhardt, Hans L.Nazi Conquest of Danzig, 1942; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 8)
    - Negley, Glenn.The Organization of Knowledge, 1942; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 9)
    - Brady, Robert R.Business as a System of Power, 1943; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 10)
    - Kotschnig, Walter M.Slaves Need No Leaders, 1943; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 11)
    - Nova, Fritz.The National Socialist Fuehrerprinzip and Its Background in German Thought, 1943; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 12)
    - Arnold, Joseph Irving.Socialism in the United States, 1944; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 13)
    - Fraenkel, Ernst.Military Occupation and the Rule of Law: Occupational Government in the Rhineland 1918-1923, 1944 (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 14)
    - Heiden, Konrad.Der Fuehrer: Hitler's Rise to Power, 1944; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 15)
    - Hermens, Ferdinand A.The Tyrants' War and the Peoples' Peace, 1944; typescript, galley proofs, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 16)
    - Kingsley, J. Donald.Representative Bureaucracy. An Interpretation of the British Civil Service, 1944; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 17)
    - Polanyi, Karl.The Great Transformation, 1944; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 18)
    - von Hayek, F. A. "The Counterrevolution of Science" and "Scientism and the Study of Society", 1941-1944; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 19)
    - Anderson, William and John M. Gaus.Research in Public Administration, 1945 (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 20)
    - Venable, Vernon.Human Nature: The Marxian View, 1945; typescript, proofs (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 21)
    - König, René.Materialien zur Soziologie der Familie, 1946; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 22)
    - Reich, Wilhelm.The Mass Psychology of Fascism, 1946; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 23)
    - Salter, J. T. (ed.).Public Men In and Out of Office, 1946; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 24)
    - Smith, Bruce L., Harold D. Lasswell, Ralph D. Casey.Communication and Public Opinion, 1946 (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 25)
    - Vontobel, Klara.Das Arbeitsethos des deutschen Protestantismus, 1946; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 26)
    - Pigors, Paul and Charles A. Meyer.Personnel Administration, 1947; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 27)
    - Flechtheim, Ossip K.Die Kommunistische Partei Deutschlands in der Weimarer Republik, 1948; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 28)
    - Spero, Sterling D.Government as Employer, 1948 (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 29)
      Typescript, reprint, related correspondence.
    - Geiger, Theodor.Aufgaben und Stellung der Intelligenz in der Gesellschaft, 1949; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 30)
    - Bakke, E. Wight.Bonds of Organization, 1950; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 31)
    - von Wiese, Leopold.Gesellschaftliche Stände und Klassen, 1950; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 32)
    - Fränger, Wilhlem.The Millenium of Hieronymus Bosch, 1951; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 33)
    - Geiger, Theodor.Soziale Umschichtungen in einer Dänischen Mittelstadt, 1951; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 34)
    - Schumpeter, Joseph A.Imperialism and Social Classes, 1951; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 35)
    - Havemann, Ernest and Patricia Salter West.They Went to College, 1952; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 36)
    - Horkheimer, Max.Survey of the Social Sciences in Western Germany, 1952; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 37)
    - Lays, Wayne A. R.Ethics for Political Decisions, 1952; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 38)
    - Edinger, Louis J.German Exile Politics. The Social Democratic Executive Committee in the Nazi Era, 1956; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 39)
    - Sutton, Francis X., Seymour E. Harris, Carl Kayson, James Tobin.The American Business Creed, 1956; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 40)
    - Berliner, Joseph S.Factory and Manager in the USSR, 1957; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 41)
    - Komarovsky, Mirra (ed.).Common Frontiers of the Social Sciences, 1957; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 42)
    - Baltzell, E. Digby.Philadelphia Gentlemen -- The Making of a National Upper Class, 1958; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 43)
    - Hunter, Floyd.Top Leadership U.S.A, 1959; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 44)
    - Inkeles, Alex and Raymond A. Bauer.The Soviet Citizen, 1959; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 45)
    - Cherniavsky, Michael.Tsar and People: Studies in Russian Myths, 1961; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 46)
    - Mendel, Arthur P.Dilemmas of Progress in Tsarist Russia, 1961; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 47)
    - Mommsen, Wolfgang. Max Weber, 1961; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 48)
    - Samuelsson, Kurt.Religion and Economic Action, 1961; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 49)
    - Gerhard, Dietrich.Alte und neue Welt in Vergleichender Geschichtsbetrachtung, 1962; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 50)
    - Habermas, Jürgen.Strukturwandel der Öffentlichkeit, 1962; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 51)
    - Hagen, Everett E.On the Theory of Social Change: How Economic Growth Begins, 1962; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 52)
    - Hintze, Otto.Staat und Verfassung, 1962; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 53)
    - LaPalombara, Joseph (ed.).Bureaucracy and Political Development, 1963; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 54)
    - Weber, Max.The Sociology of Religion, 1963; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 55)
    - Aronson, Sidney H.Status and Kinship in the Higher Civil Service, 1964; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 56)
    - Hintze, Otto.Soziologie und Geschichte, 1964; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 57)
    - Marcuse, Herbert. "Industrialisierung und Kapitalismus", 1964?; mimeograph (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 58)
    - Thompson, E.P.The Making of the English Working Class, 1964; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 59)
    - Moore, Barrington, Jr.Social Origins of Dictatorship and Democracy: Lord and Peasant in the Making of the Modern World, 1966; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 60)
    - Hintze, Otto.Regierung und Verwaltung, 1967; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 61)
    - Weber, Max.Economy and Society, 1968; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 62)
    - Glassman, Ronald.Political History of Latin America, 1970; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 63)
    - Undated, typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 64)
      Ashby, Sir Eric. Any Person, Any Study (1972); Ben-David, Joseph. American Higher Education (1972).
    - Shils, Edward.The Intellectuals and the Powers and Other Essays, 1972; typescript, reprints (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 65)
    - Beasley, W. G.The Meiji Restoration, 1973; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 66)
    - Eisenstadt, S. N. and Stein Rokkan (eds.).Building States and Nations. Vol. I-II, 1973; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 67)
    - Bell, Daniel.The Coming of Post-Industrial Society. A Venture in Social Forecasting, 1973; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 68)
    - Fallers, Lloyd A., Undated (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 69)
      Inequality, Social Stratification Reconsidered (1973); The Social Anthropology of the Nation-State (1974). Typescripts.
    - Berger, Monroe.Real and Imagined Worlds, the Novel and Social Science, 1977; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 70)
    - Dyson, Kenneth H. F.The State Tradition in Western Europe: A Study of an Idea and Institution, 1980; typescript, reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 71)
    - Skocpol, Theda.States and Social Revolutions, 1980; reprints (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 72)
    - Tilly, Charles.Big Structures, Large Processes, Huge Comparisons, 1986; reprint (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 73)
    - Walder, Andrew.Communist Neo-Traditionalism, Work and Authority in Chinese Industry, 1986; typescript (Box 8A (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 74)
- Course and Lecture Notes, 1943-1986; 4; 38 file folders
  This series contains course notes, outlines, background materials, book notes, and student papers from the many courses taught by Bendix at the University of Chicago, the University of California, Berkeley, as well as from his guest professorships in Germany.
  - Community and Intellectual Life, Undated (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 1)
  - Family, Religion, Ethnicity. Freshman Seminar, 1985 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 2)
  - Historical and Comparative Methods, 1967 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 3)
  - History of Political Theory / History of Political Thought, Undated (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 4-5)
  - History of Social Theory, 1958-1963 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 6)
  - Industrial Societies, Undated (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 7)
  - Major Turning Points in Western Social Organization, 1990-1991 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 8)
  - Max Weber Seminar, Winter 1967-1968 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 9)
  - Max Weber Seminar, 1978-1979 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 10)
  - Methodology and Value Theory in the Works of Max Weber. Seminar with Wolfgang Schluchter, Fall 1986 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 11)
  - Large Scale Organizations / Organizations and Institutions, Undated (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 12-13)
  - Political Science 1, 1972 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 14)
  - Political Sociology, 1961 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 15)
  - Process and Character of Modernization, 1982-1983 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 16)
  - Social Organization of Modern Western Societies, Undated (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 17)
  - Social Psychology, Undated (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 18)
  - Social Stratification, Undated (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 19-20)
  - Social Science 2. University of Chicago, 1943-1945 (Box 9 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 21)
  - Sociology 1 (taught with W. Kornhauser, D. Matza), 1960 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 1)
  - Sociology and Social Institutions (Sociology 2), 1954 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 2)
  - Sociology of Science / Sociology of Knowledge, Undated (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 3-4)
  - Study of Group Behavior, Undated (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 5)
  - Themes in Western Political Thought, 1973 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 6)
  - Theories of Comparative Analysis, Undated (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 7)
  - Theories of Democratic Development, Undated (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 8)
  - Lectures, seminar. Berlin and Freiburg, Summer 1963 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 9)
  - German seminar, lectures. Freie Universität, Berlin, Winter 1964-1965 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 10)
  - Probleme der Literatursoziologie. Seminar with Walter Killy, Göttingen, 1970 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 11)
  - Sociology of Knowledge / Max Weber. Konstanz, 1971 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 12)
  - Freiheit und historisches Schicksal. Heidelberger Max Weber Vorlesungen, 1981 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 13)
  - American managerial ideologies. Student papers, 1949-1950 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 14)
  - Industrialism. Student papers and notes, 1956 (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 15)
  - Student papers, various topics, Undated (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 16)
  - Comments on student papers, Undated (Box 10 (4-Course and Lecture Notes), Folder 17)
- Published and Unpublished Writings by Others, 5; 128 file folders
  This series contains reprints, clippings and typescripts of articles by other authors collected by Bendix. Many of the texts are mimeographed typescripts and were used by Bendix in his courses and lectures.
  - Adams, Stuart. "Origins of U.S. Occupational Elites: 1900-1955", mimeograph (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 1)
  - Alber, Jens. "The West German Welfare State in Transition", 1986 September 22-1986 September 26; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 2)
  - Albert, Hans, Undated; reprints (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 3)
  - Amare, Neway. "Unequal Exchange and Development of Underdevelopment". Dissertation abstract, 1989 December 1; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 4)
  - Assmus, Erika. "Die Bedeutung der Parteischulung im Rahmen der Kaderpolitik", Undated (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 5)
    Typescript, undated.
  - Barber, Bernard, Undated; reprint (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 6)
  - Beals, Alan. "Conflict and Interlocal Festivals in a South Indian Region", Undated; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 7)
  - Bell, Daniel, Undated; clippings (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 8)
  - Berger, Bennett M., Undated (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 9)
    "Racist Plastic Uptight. Criticisms of Middle Class America". Mimeographed, undated; "Student Unrest and the Crisis in the Universities". Mimeographe, 1969; "Autobiography and Sociology". Mimeographe, undated.
  - Bisson, Thomas. "Some Characteristics of Mediterranean Territorial Power in the Twelfth Century", 1978; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 10)
  - Bodemann, Y. Michal. "Everett Cherrington Hughes (1897-1983)", typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 11)
  - Bouwsma, William J. "Models of the Educated Man in the West", 1974 June 24; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 12)
  - Brandel, F., Undated (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 13)
    "Afterthoughts on Material Civilization". Mimeo, undated; "Capitalism and Dividing up the World". Mimeo., undated; "The Market Economy and Capitalism". Mimeo., undated.
  - Brutzkus, Boris. "The Historical Peculiarities of the Social and Economic Development of Russia", 1934; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 14)
  - Burawoy, Michael. "Two Methods in Search of Science: Skocpol versus Trotsky", ca. 1986; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 15)
  - Clark, Burton R. "The New University", 1967 August 27; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 16)
  - Cleveland, Alfred S. "Some Political Aspects of Organized Industry", 1946 October; typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 17)
  - Cohn, Bernard S. and McKim Marriott. "Networks and Centers in the Integration of Indian Civilization", 1959; photocopy of typescript (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 18)
  - Coser, Lewis A., Undated; reprints (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 19)
  - Davis, Kingsley, Undated; reprints (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 20)
  - Davis, Robert C. "The Public's Image of Science and Scientists", 1958; mimeograph (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 21)
  - Erikson, Erik. "Psychoanalysis and Ongoing History. A Letter", 1962 October; mimeograph (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 22)
  - Evers, Hans-Dieter, Undated; reprints (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 23)
  - Ezrahi, Yaron. "The Political Resources of Science", 1969; typescript, photocopy (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 24)
  - Ferrarotti, Franco. "Introductory Remarks on Ideology and Sociology", 1966 September (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 25)
    Typescript, photocopy, Evian conference.
  - Fox, Renée C., Undated; reprints (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 26)
  - Friedberg, Maurice. "The Third Soviet Writers Congress: An Appraisal", 1959; mimeograph (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 27)
  - Friedeburg, Ludwig von, Undated; reprint (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 28)
  - Friedrichs, Robert W. "The Role of Science in the Consolidation of the Chinese Revolution", Undated; mimeograph (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 29)
  - Friedson, Eliot, Undated (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 30)
    "Unprofessional Consequences of Professionalism". Mimeo., July 1969; "Dominant Professions, Bureaucracy, and Client Services". Mimeo., 1970.
  - Gella, Aleksander. "The End of the Old Structure of the Polish Intelligentsia", 1967; mimeograph (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 31)
  - Gerth, Hans, Undated; reprint (Box 11 (5-Published and Unpublished Writings by Others), Folder 32)